Records of the Education Sector
World Bank Group Archives
- Director and Front Office records, 1964 - 1992, 1995 - 2013; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-01; 27.46 linear feet of textual records
  The series also consists of a small set of briefing books (1997 - 2002, 2009) prepared by the sector primarily for senior officials including President Wolfensohn at the World Education Forum held in Dakar in 2000, for Wolfensohn's meeting with the Bureau of African Ministers of the Association for the Development of Education in Africa (ADEA, 1997 - 2000, and a quarterly briefing book for Managing Director Mamphela Ramphele (2002). There are briefing books (1998 - 2002) for HDNED director external meetings and events and a briefing book of Director King (2009).
  NRIC correspondence and related records
  Also included in the series are several correspondence files (1975 - 1986) authored by department senior management, division chiefs, and advisers that were originally sent to the Non-Regional Information Center (NRIC) and arranged under the Bank-wide classification. Files are titled "general" and "agriculture modular instruction" and include mostly internal memoranda, letters, and cables that cover the various sector activities such as policy work, project related training and workshops, unit work program and objectives, education lending and economic and sector work reviews, and liaison with partners. Study outlines and papers, Terms of Reference, meeting summaries, proposals, final reports, and bound publications are sometimes filed with correspondence.
  Most records in the series are in English. However, a small amount of correspondence and other items are in French and the 1979 Education Sector Policy press release is also in French, Spanish, and Arabic.
  Most files are arranged by subject. Chronological records are arranged chronologically by year and a portion of these files are further arranged by month.
  Certain "series" of records originally maintained in the semi-centralized Non-Regional Informatoin Center (NRIC) that relate to a specific function or unit, in this case the Education Sector "general" files, were arrranged in this functional department series.
  Accruals are expected.
  Most records were transferred directly to the Archives by the Human Development Network, Education Team (HDNED) and previous units between 1992 and 2014, in accordance with approved records retention schedules. Other records were maintained in the Non-Regional Information Center (NRIC) that centrally managed records created by sector departments, until its closure in 1987; these centralized files were accessioned into the Archives' holdings in 1994. Elizabeth King chronological files (1987 - 1992) were brought with her when she transferred to a new position in the Poverty and Human Resources Division (PRDPH) in 1993. In 1994, these files were sent to the Archives by PRDPH with other unit records.
  * See Records of the Education Sector - Education Sector Board records ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-04](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/education-sector-board-records)) for chronological records of the sector board staff including the sector manager, as well as subject files and meeting records regarding sector strategy, partnership collaboration, and other oversight matters.
  * See Records of the Education Sector - Operations research ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-10](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/operations-research)) for records regarding collaboration between the department's Research and Education Policy Divisions and preparation of the sector policy study on education in Sub-Saharan Africa.
  * See Records of the Education Sector - Policy and best practice development ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA 11-07](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/policy-and-best-practice-development)) for records related to the development of sector policy and strategy papers, as well as the establishment andproceedings of external advisory panels.
  * See Records of the Education Sector - Partnerships and program collaboration ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-02](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/partnerships-and-program-collaboration)) for more records related to the management of partnerships with external organizations and collaborative programs.
  * See Records of the Education Sector - Knowledge and learning events ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-01](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/knowledge-and-learning-events)) for records related to senior management and staff participation and presentations at conferences and other learning events.
  * See Records of the Education Sector - Knowledge management products ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-09](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/knowledge-management-products)) for records maintained by the knowledge management unit that include director presentations and papers.
  * See Records of the Education sector - Budget management ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-05](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/budget-management)) for related records of fiscal year business planning and reviews.
  * See Central Files - Operational sector files ([WB IBRD/IDA ADMCF-07](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/operational-sector-files)) for records related to the Bank's Educator Sector that were managed in the central files system from the time of the Education Division, Projects Department (PRJED), and successor departments from 1965 to mid-1987.
  Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.
  - Elizabeth King - Chronological File - September 1987 - December 1988, 1987-09-03 - 1988-12-22; 01213812
  - Poverty Reduction Strategy Papers - 2000 - 2001, 2000-03-24 - 2001-03-31; 30037786
  - Fast Track Initiative - Education for All Next Steps for Latin America and Caribbean, 2002-06-18 - 2002-07-01; 30037787
  - Outcomes From Dakar [Maris O'Rourke], 1999-05-11 - 2000-01-14; 30037788
  - Development Committee Papers - 2001 - 2004, 2001-09-18 - 2004-03-26; 30037789
  - Kagia, Ruth - Costa Rica - Focus on Education and Computerization - January 2002, 1973-05-29 - 2002-01-31; 30037790
  - Partnerships - Fiscal Year [FY] 2001, 2001-01-12 - 2001-05-15; 30037791
  - Executive Development Cohort One Module III - 2 - 14 March 1997, 1997-01-19 - 1997-04-13; 30037792
  - International Development Goal Directors File - Fiscal Year [FY] 2001, 2001-01-23 - 2001-04-27; 30037796
  - User Fees Background Materials - April 2001, 2001-02-01 - 2002-02-28; 30037797
  - Country Summaries and Education Status Data, 1997-06-23 - 1997-07-01; 30037798
  - Kagia, Ruth - Country Assistance Strategy Review, 1995-03-27 - 2000-06-02; 30037799
  - Kagia, Ruth - Education For All [EFA] Fast Track Initiative - Internal Meetings, Comments, Presentations, Miscellaneous, 2002-06-19 - 2003-11-24; 30037800
  - Education For All - Fast Track Initiative Regional and Country Specific - 2002, 2002-06-15 - 2002-09-20; 30037847
  - Education For All - Fast Track Initiative Emails - Correspondences - Fiscal Year [FY] 2002, 2002-04-30 - 2002-07-01; 30037848
  - Education For All / Fast Track Initiative Staffing - 2002 - 2003, 2002-07-01 - 2004-10-31; 30037849
  - Education For All Fast Track Initiative - Fiscal Year [FY] 2001, 2001-09-18 - 2002-07-01; 30037850
  - Education The World Bank - Presentation Slides, 1998-10-12; 30037857
  - Kagia, Ruth - Education For All Fast Track Initiative - Concept Note and Financing Paper, 2002-04-17 - 2002-08-07; 30037858
  - Kagia, Ruth - Education For All - 2001 - 2002, 2001-12-21 - 2002-05-09; 30037859
  - Education For All - 2001, 2001-08-01 - 2001-11-30; 30037860
  - Education Action Plan - Fiscal Year 1997, 1997-01-01 - 1997-12-31; 30037861
  - Demand Side Financing in Education - An Operational Review, 1996-05-01 - 1996-06-30; 30037862
  - Overview of European Bilateral Aid in Education - 3 December 2001, 2000-05-01 - 2001-07-03; 30037863
  - Kagia, Ruth - Poverty Reduction Strategy Paper, 1997-09-01 - 2000-02-09; 30037864
  - Education For All / Fast Track Initiative - Donors Meeting and Comments - 2002 - 2003, 2002-05-02 - 2003-11-19; 30037865
  - Education - PED - General, 1981-03-27 - 1983-08-30; 01064411
  - Operational Policy - Education - PED - General, 1978-02-27 - 1980-05-06; 01057488
  - Operational Policy - P - Education - PED - General, 1984-01-25 - 1986-06-30; 01057523
  - Education - PED - General Documents - Volume 1, 1980-02-01 - 1983-08-25; 01064412
  - Education - PED - General Documents - Volume 2, 1975-05-01 - 1983-10-31; 01064413
  - Education - PED - Agricultural Modular Instruction, 1979-06-27 - 1980-12-12; 01064415
  - Education - PED - Agricultural Modular Instruction Documents, 1978-08-01 - 1980-02-29; 01064416
  - Operational Policy - Education - PED - General Documents - 1984 - 1986, 1984-02-01 - 1986-12-31; 01065126
  - Sector - Education - 1987 / 1989 Correspondence - Volume 1, 1987-02-02 - 1987-05-11; 01156125
  - Research papers on education - set, 1973-01-01 - 1979-12-31; 01105610
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization [UNESCO] - IBRD - Cooperative Progress [CP] - Technical Assistance - Background Papers - G10-10/6 - Volume 1, 1973-01-23 - 1984-04-28; 01105609
  - Operational Policy - Education - PED - General - 1978 - 1980, 1980-06-05 - 1980-08-11; 30048662
  - Education - PED - General Documents - Volume 3, 1982-06-01 - 1983-10-31; 30048679
  - DiSCuS completed projects, G5-7/2 - set, 1964-01-01 - 1969-12-31; 01105608
  - DiSCuS ongoing projects from A to Z, G5-7/2 (data sheets) - 2v, 1966-01-01 - 1976-12-31; 01105607
  - Sub-Saharan Africa policy paper: background papers, G5-4/8-4 - 2v, 1982-01-01 - 1986-12-31; 01105605
  - Sub-Saharan Africa: bibligraphy by T. Wagaw, G5-4/8-3 - 2v, 1982-01-01 - 1983-12-31; 01105604
  - Sub-Saharan education: background, policy papers, reports and comments - G5-4/8 - set, 1985-01-01 - 1988-12-31; 01105603
  - Sub-Saharan Africa Advisory Panel, Dijon Meeting, G5-4/8-2 - set, 1982-01-01 - 1985-12-31; 01105601
  - Sub-Saharan education: background, policy papers, reports and comments - G5-4/8 - box, 1985-01-01 - 1988-12-31; 01105602
  - Sub-Saharan education: background, policy papers, reports and comments - G5-4/8 - box, 1985-01-01 - 1988-12-31; 01105600
  - Education sector papers, G4/7/3 - box, 1978-01-01 - 1987-12-31; 01105599
  - Seminar on World Bank Policy in Education, G4/7/3 - set, 1980-06-01 - ?; 01105598
  - Education policy, reports, G4/7/2, - 2v, 1974-01-01 - 1980-12-31; 01105597
  - Education policy, G4/7/1 - 2v, 1974-01-01 - 1981-12-31; 01105596
  - Task Force on Issues and Strategies for Meeting Needs of High Level Agricultural Training in Africa - set, 1986-01-01 - 1987-12-31; 01105594
  - Management Seminar, November 1985, G2-25/2 - set, 1985-11-01 - ?; 01105593
  - Issues in education projects seminar, G2-25 - 2v, 1986-05-17 - 1987-01-09; 01105592
  - Tools for sector analysis seminar G2-24 - set, 1986-11-17 - 1986-11-19; 01105591
  - International Fund for Education Research. (IFER) G2-18 - 2v, 1973-01-01 - 1984-12-31; 01105551
  - Education policy analysis seminar, G2-23 - 2v, 1986-09-16 - 1987-07-09; 01105554
  - Textbook Seminar, November 1985, G2-21 - set, 1985-11-01 - ?; 01105553
  - Financing of education seminar, G2-20 - set, 1985-01-01 - 1987-12-31; 01105552
  - Education news, G2-17 - set, 1986-01-01 - 1987-12-31; 01105550
  - Education Sector Retreat background papers, January 1986, G2-16 - 2v, 1986-01-01 - ?; 01105549
  - Management of Education Projects Seminar, G2-15 - set, 1986-05-01 - ?; 01105548
  - School Libraries Media Centers Seminar, G2-14 - set, 1982-01-01 - ?; 01105547
  - Study on Human Potential Seminar, G2-14/8 - set, 1982-01-01 - 1983-12-31; 01105546
  - Education Sector Lending Seminars, G2-14/6 - 2v, 1985-01-01 - 1987-12-31; 01105545
  - Training general: reports, G2-14.1/2 - 2v, 1981-01-01 - 1983-12-31; 01105544
  - Training general, G2-14 - set, 1983-01-01 - 1986-12-31; 01105543
  - World Education Forum - Dakar Senegal Briefing Documents for Mr. James Wolfensohn, 2000-03-02 - 2000-04-28; 30037856
  - Meeting With Bureau of African Ministries of Association for the Development of Education in Africa [ADEA] - Briefing for Mr. James Wolfensohn - 11 February 1997, 1997-02-11 - 2000-12-31; 30037855
  - Higher Education Task Force at Human Development Week 2000, 1998-03-01 - 2000-03-01; 30037854
  - Chronological Records - Nicholas Kraft, 2005-10-12 - 2006-12-22; 30128407
  - Laporte, Bruno - Human Development Council Business Review Meeting - 21 June 2000, 2000-06-12 - 2001-06-21; 30037853
  - Kagia, Ruth - Materials on UNICEF and UNESCO - January 2002, 1999-06-06 - 2002-01-30; 30037852
  - Quarterly Briefing - Dr. Mamphela Ramphele - 10 September 2002, 2002-07-09 - 2002-10-10; 30037851
  - Operational Policy - Education - PED - Agriculture Modular Instruction - 1981 - 1983, 1981-02-13 - 1983-12-31; 01065127
  - Deadline Letters - EXC - Correspondence, 1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31; 01676834
  - Travel / Leave / Timesheets - Maris O'Rourke - Correspondence, 1995-11-01 - 1997-12-01; 01676846
  - Letters - Acceptance / Invitation / Regret - Visitors - Maris O'Rourke - Correspondence, 1996-02-01 - 1997-12-01; 01676841
  - Deadline Letters - HDNVP - Correspondence, 1999-01-01 - 2000-01-31; 01676837
  - Correspondence Log - Correspondence, 1999-04-01 - 1999-12-01; 01676832
  - Deadline Log Book - Correspondence 2, 1998-08-01 - 1998-12-31; 01676805
  - Deadline Log Book - Correspondence 1, 1998-01-01 - 1998-07-31; 01676804
  - Chronological Files - Maris O'Rourke - Correspondence 7, 1998-04-01 - 1998-12-31; 01676802
  - Chronological Files - Maris O'Rourke - Correspondence 6, 1997-01-01 - 1997-10-31; 01676742
  - Chronological Files - Maris O'Rourke - Correspondence 5, 1996-10-01 - 1996-12-31; 01676741
  - Chronological Files - Maris O'Rourke - Correspondence 4, 1996-07-01 - 1996-10-01; 01676740
  - Chronological Files - Maris O'Rourke - Correspondence 3, 1996-04-01 - 1996-07-01; 01676739
  - Chronological Files - Maris O'Rourke - Correspondence 2, 1996-01-01 - 1996-03-31; 01676738
  - Chronological Files - Maris O'Rourke - Correspondence 1, 1995-10-01 - 1995-12-31; 01676737
  - Correspondence Tracking - Office of the President [EXC] - March - April 2000, 2000-01-03 - 2001-04-20; 30123593
  - Correspondence Tracking - Office of the Senior Vice President and Head of Network [HDNVP] - May 2000, 2000-05-05 - 2000-12-15; 30123595
  - Mr. Wolfensohns Meeting With The Bureau of African Ministers of The Association For The Development of Education in Africa [ADEA], 1997-02-11; 30123633
  - Correspondence Tracking - Office of the Senior Vice President and Head of Network [HDNVP] - June - November 2000, 2000-06-02 - 2000-11-28; 30123597
  - Correspondence Tracking - Office of the Senior Vice President and Head of Network [HDNVP] - April - March 2000, 2000-01-03 - 2000-04-30; 30123592
  - Directors Chronological Records - Calendar Year [CY] 2003 - Ruth Kagia - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED], 2002-09-04 - 2003-12-19; 30123538
  - Directors Chronological Records - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] - Calendar Year [CY] 2002, 2002-01-03 - 2002-12-01; 30123537
  - Office of the Senior Vice President and Head of Network [HDNVP] - Office of the President [EXC] External Correspondence [En-Corr] - April - August 2001, 2001-04-25 - 2001-08-14; 30123535
  - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] - Directors Chronological Records - 2001, 2000-09-27 - 2001-12-31; 30123528
  - Correspondence Tracking Office of the Senior Vice President and Head of Network [HDNVP] - November - December 2000, 2000-05-16 - 2000-12-11; 30123510
  - Office of the Senior Vice President and Head of Network [HDNVP] - Office of the President [EXC] External Correspondence [En-Corr] - August 2001, 2001-07-10 - 2001-12-05; 30123513
  - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] - Office of the President [EXC] External Correspondence [En-Corr] - January - April 2001, 2001-01-09 - 2001-04-19; 30123512
  - Office of the Senior Vice President and Head of Network [HDNVP] External Correspondence [En-Corr] - January 2001, 2001-01-19 - 2001-12-21; 30123511
  - Education Group Of The Human Development Network [HDNED] - Chronological Records 2003 - 2004, 2003-02-10 - 2004-03-18; 30123508
  - Education Group Of The Human Development Network [HDNED] - Office of the Senior Vice President and Head of Network [HDNVP] External Correspondence [En-Corr] - 2005, 2005-01-12 - 2005-10-12; 30123507
  - Education Group Of The Human Development Network [HDNED] - Office of the President [EXC] and Office of the Senior Vice President and Head of Network [HDNVP] External Correspondence [En-Corr] - 2006 and 2007, 2006-03-01 - 2007-08-21; 30123506
  - Education Group Of The Human Development Network [HDNED] - Office of the Senior Vice President and Head of Network [HDNVP] External Correspondence [En-Corr] - 2004, 2004-01-21 - 2004-12-23; 30123489
  - Education Group Of The Human Development Network [HDNED] - Office of the Senior Vice President and Head of Network [HDNVP] External Correspondence [En-Corr] - 2002 - 2003, 2002-04-09 - 2003-12-12; 30123488
  - Directors Chronological Records - Calendar Year [CY] 2004 Through Calendar Year [CY] 2006 - Education Group Of The Human Development Network; [HDNED] - Marga, 2004-01-15 - 2007-03-13; 30123487
  - Elizabeth King - Chronological File - April to June 1990, 1990-04-04 - 1990-06-05; 30431336
  - Elizabeth King - Chronological File - January to March 1990, 1990-01-05 - 1990-03-29; 30431335
  - Elizabeth King - Chronological File - July to December 1989, 1989-07-03 - 1989-12-14; 30431334
  - Elizabeth King - Chronological File - May to June 1989, 1989-05-01 - 1989-06-30; 30431333
  - Elizabeth King - Chronological File - March to April 1989, 1989-03-01 - 1989-04-27; 30431332
  - Elizabeth King - Chronological File - January to February 1989, 1988-06-21 - 1989-02-27; 30431331
  - Elizabeth King - Chronological File - June 1990 to March 1991, 1990-06-01 - 1991-03-12; 30431337
  - Elizabeth King - Chronological File - July 1991 to March 1992, 1991-07-01 - 1992-03-30; 30431338
  - Beth King - Sector Director - May - June 2010 - Meetings and Consultations - Chronological Records - Volume 1, 2010-04-01 - 2010-06-15; 30254460
  - Beth King - Sector Director - January 2009 - Briefing Book, 2009-01-01 - 2009-01-31; 30254463
  - Beth King - Sector Director - June - December 2010 - Meetings and Consultations - Chronological Records, 2010-06-30 - 2010-10-26; 30254462
  - Beth King - Sector Director - May - June 2010 - Meetings and Consultations - Chronological Records - Volume 2, 2010-04-06 - 2010-06-27; 30254461
  - Beth King - Sector Director - January - February 2010 - Meetings and Consultations - Chronological Records, 2009-12-23 - 2010-05-04; 30254459
  - Beth King - Sector Director - January - May 2010 - Meetings and Consultations - Chronological Records, 2010-04-09 - 2010-05-06; 30254458
  - Beth King - Sector Director - April 2009 - May 2010 - Correspondence - Chronological Records, 2009-06-02 - 2010-05-11; 30254457
  - DGF Proposals - Fiscal Year [FY] 2011 - March 2010 - Chronological Records, 2009-11-06 - 2010-03-25; 30254456
  - Beth King - Sector Director - March - June 2013 - Correspondence - Chronological Records, 2013-03-04 - 2013-06-15; 30254455
  - Beth King - Sector Director - October 2012 - February 2013 - Correspondence - Chronological Records, 2012-10-15 - 2013-02-26; 30254454
  - Beth King - Sector Director - July - October 2012 - Correspondence - Chronological Records, 2012-07-02 - 2013-06-18; 30254453
  - Beth King - Sector Director - April - June 2012 - Correspondence - Chronological Records, 2012-04-02 - 2012-06-14; 30254452
  - Beth King - Sector Director - February - March 2012 - Correspondence - Chronological Records, 2011-09-19 - 2012-03-29; 30254451
  - Beth King - Sector Director - January - June 2010 - Correspondence - Chronological Records, 2010-01-14 - 2010-06-22; 30254450
  - Beth King - Sector Director - October - December 2011 - Correspondence - Chronological Records, 2011-10-03 - 2011-12-19; 30254449
  - Beth King - Sector Director - July - September 2011 - Correspondence - Chronological Records, 2011-02-28 - 2011-09-26; 30254448
  - Beth King - Sector Director - January - July 2013 - Correspondence - Chronological Records, 2013-01-02 - 2013-07-31; 30254447
  - Beth King - Sector Director - August - December 2012 - Correspondence - Chronological Records, 2012-08-03 - 2012-12-31; 30254446
  - Beth King - Sector Director - May - July 2012 - Correspondence - Chronological Records, 2012-05-18 - 2012-07-31; 30254445
  - Beth King - Sector Director - January - June 2012 - Correspondence - Chronological Records, 2012-01-26 - 2012-06-21; 30254444
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization [UNESCO] - IBRD - Cooperative Progress [CP] - Technical Assistance - Background Papers - G10-10/6 - Volume 2, 1973-02-01 - 1983-07-27; 30462955
- Budget management, 1997 - 2001, 2004; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-05; 3.78 linear feet of textual records
  Series consists of records maintained by the front office of the Education Team of the Human Development Network (HDNED) related to fiscal year business planning and reviews in preparation for budget allocation and monitoring. Business plans were developed by the sector director and advisers and were subsequently endorsed by the Education Sector Board on which the director served as chair. Records were predominantly created between 1997 and 2001 by Directors Maris O'Rourke and Ruth Kagia and other senior staff including Bruno LaPorte, Jamil Salmi, and Sukai Prom-Jackson. The records provide contextual information about the organization of HDNED teams, the sector's thematic activities, strategic objectives, support to Bank regions, partnerships, spending, and lending.
  Record types within the series include memoranda, hard copy emails, budget sheets, staffing lists, cost and expenditure tables, guidelines, hard copy presentation slides, HDN issues notes, and draft and final reports concerning the sector'sbusiness plans, mid-term review of work programs, and retrospective reviews. These records, particularly the reports that are in table form, detail the sector's various work programs, such as early childhood education, under which the program's various themes, activities, projects and outcomes, and regions of focus are outlined.
  Correspondence is between HDNED director or other senior staff and the Human Development Network Vice Presidency (HDNVP), Human Development Network Operations (HDNOP), and Strategy, Finance, Risk and Resource Management (SFRRM) regarding the planning process and budget matters, and allocation of funds to the regions and HD anchor.
  Series also includes a file from 2004 containing records related to global partnerships and programs, specifically preparation of the Development Grant Facility (DGF) work program, budget, and Global Program and Partnerships (GPP) portfolio review. Among the records are a hard copy presentation on DGF and proposed DGF budget FY05 to executive directors, hard copy emails attached to DGF summary information with budget requests and allocations, DGF work program task outlines, draft report, and DGF Council correspondence and reports on allocations for HDN. Correspondence is mainly between HDNED staff and DGF manager.
  Records are mostly arranged chronologically.
  Records were transferred to the Archives by the Education Team, Human Development Network (HDNED) in multiple transfers between 2001 and 2011, in accordance with approved records retention and disposal schedules.
  No further accruals are expected.